<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
<string-array name="program_names">
    <item>Neural Networks</item>
    <item>Unsupervised and Reinforcement Learning</item>
    <item>Business Entrepreneurship</item>
    <item>Big Data Tools</item>
    <item>IT Project Management</item>
    <item>Advanced Database</item>
    <item>Java Programming</item>
    <item>Web Application</item>
    <item>Mobile App Development</item>
    <item>Software System Design</item>
</string-array>

<string-array name="program_descriptions">
    <item>This course covers artificial neural networks and their practical applications. \n
        Coursework emphasizes fundamental models and algorithms starting with McCulloch-Pitts and Perceptron models, \n
        Multi-Layer Perceptron (MLP) networks, backpropagation algorithm, activation functions,\n
        convolutional neural networks, and recurrent neural networks.
    </item>
    <item>In the first half of this course, students will be exposed to unsupervised learning concepts,\n
            examples and algorithms, such as data clustering concepts, k-means clustering, \n
            the expectation-maximization algorithm and the Gaussian mixture models, \n
            principal components analysis, independent component analysis and factor analysis.
    </item>
    <item>Software Engineering Technology not only has unlimited potential for transforming the way organizations operate and their decision-making capabilities but,\n
            in addition, it provides opportunities for innovation and entrepreneurship. \n
            In the latter sense, new ideas are conceived, developed and deployed for the advancement of society.
    </item>
    <item>In this course, students will be introduced to large scale learning: distributed learning.\n
            The concepts of distributed storage systems and parallel processing will be discussed. \n
            Storage types for big data (NoSQL) and big data tools (Hadoop eco system, YARN and Apache Spark) will be explained and students will gain hands-on experience by applying the big data tools in real world applications.
    </item>
    <item>Students are taught the concepts and basic functions of Project Management, and the integration of these concepts and functions into a coherent project management system.\n
            Also, role of the project manager and the project management team in implementing and controlling projects.
    </item>
    <item>This course is intended to expand the student’s knowledge of business databases using data RDBMS and NoSQL driven systems.\n
            The course introduces students to the steps required to install and configure a database server and development system.
    </item>
    <item>Building on fundamentals of Object-Oriented programming, this course covers Component-based Application Development and Database Connectivity using the Java programming language.\n
            Coursework emphasizes how to create complex GUI applications with Java programming language, interacting with the databases using JDBC, and Java collections framework.
    </item>
    <item> In this course, students will learn how to design, code, and test a full-stack web application.\n
        \nThe major topics covered include:\n
        1. Frontend and backend development\n
        2. Connecting to various databases or data stores \n
        4. Securing and deploying complex web applications on production servers.\n
    </item>
    <item>In this mobile apps course, students will gain hands-on experience in developing and deploying mobile applications on the Android platform. \n
            Coursework emphasizes how to create advanced Graphical User Interfaces (GUIs), handle events,\n
            access remote services, store and retrieve data on the device, display maps, and use other Android APIs
    </item>
    <item>This project-based course emphasizes Software Engineering design derived from a set of Requirements Specifications. \n
            Students are introduced to software engineering design principles, concepts and tasks.\n
            Design principles are applied to software architecture, software interfaces, software components, database and user interfaces.
    </item>
</string-array>

</resources>